你真是没救了
You're beyond help.
别一惊一乍的 行吗
Whoa, relax, jumpy.
我有个办法让能量保持稳定
I've got a new idea...
这样主体框架就不会爆炸了
怎么还摔上东西了
Uh, did you just throw that?
别...别过来
Stay... Stay back.
你们叮铃咣啷的在这儿干什么呢
What in the seven sumps is all this racket?
喂 今天气儿又不太顺吗
Oi, one of those days, huh?
天才和疯子一线之隔
You know those ugly twins,
难免会有点小摩擦
genius and madness.
那能不能让疯子先出去一下啊
Maybe take the madness outside.
我这儿还得继续做生意呢
I still got a business to...
你这是又闹哪出啊
What's gotten into him?
《英雄联盟:双城之战》
第二季第七集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
嘿 回回神儿
Hey, spaceboy,
别让我在这自言自语啊
I'm not talking to myself over here.
你到底是怎么回事
What is up with you?
一整天都不在状态
You've been out of it all day.
我感觉一睁眼就来错了宇宙了
I feel like I woke up in the wrong universe.
我看你是熬夜熬的吧
This is what happens when you stay up all night.
神经元突触不听使唤了
Those synapses start firing around
就跟鼻涕虫喝醉酒一样
like drunk slugs.
我们还有大把时间为竞赛做准备呢
There's still plenty of time before the competition.
放心 全都能搞定的
Okay? We'll work out the kinks.
不是有我呢吗
I've got you.
什么风把底城的大人物给吹来了
Ah, if it isn't Zaun's royalty.
给大人请安
My liege.
快过来坐
Sit down.
嘿嘿 小不点 怎么还耷拉个脸呢
Hey, hey, little man. Trouble in paradise?
就是项目上遇到了点小磕绊
Just the usual project woes.
咱俩差不多
Tell me about it.
好不容易将裂沟废气变废为宝了
We finally got the hybrids to feed off the fissure gases,
可是转化率实在太低了 一直提高不了
but the conversion rate's way too low.
这样下去
They hardly grow.
还是没有办法实现全城空气的净化啊
They're nowhere near robust enough to purify all the air down here.
那得建成百上千个系统吧
Unless you plant a million of them.
那根本不可能
No way we're doing that.
土壤培育还有水渗透的方法 我们都试过了
And we've tried cultivating the soil, infusing the water.
全都不行
No luck.
我先出去一下
I'll be right back.
得 去吧 不撞南墙不回头啊
Oh, no. Go. Save him from himself.
没有她 你可怎么办啊
Where would you be without her?
嗨 格...
Hey, Gert.
不行
No.
勇敢点
Oh, come on.
- 嗨 格尔... - 嘿 格尔特
- Hey... - Hey, Gert.
什么时候能再看一次 炼金姐妹的表演啊
Do the Chem Sisters have another show coming up?
麦罗可是被迷得团团转
Mylo here is a big fan.
他现在根本停不下来
Like, huge.
是吗
Cool.
对了
Uh, yeah,
老大安排我们去给你俩的那个
the old man's gonna let us play the party the night before
创新者竞赛的赛前派对助兴
that Innovators Competition you all are gunning for.
没有你 他们可怎么办呀
What would they do without you?
多少会有点手足无措吧
There would probably be some arm-flailing.
其实 开了这酒馆之后 我学会了一件事
You know, one thing I learned as a bartender:
忙着把每位客人照顾好的同时
As good as it feels to pour everyone's drink,
给自己也应该倒上一杯
you need to fill your own cup
犒劳犒劳自己
every now and again.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
你觉得我这是在耽误自己
You think I'm holding myself back.
我觉着 你的聪明才干 泡在这酒馆可惜了
I think you're too smart to spend your life in a bar.
嗨 教授
Hey, professor.
- 教授  - 我是错过思想碰撞的盛会了吗
- Professor? - Am I late for a gathering of the minds?
发现自己被推入平行时空
One can't shout from the rooftops
兴奋地冲上屋顶大喊大叫之后
about being thrust into parallel dimensions
免不了会感到有些不适
without awkward consequences.
异常点
It seems
当它将我们从固有认知中的现实 抽离的那一刻
the anomaly which dislodged us from our proverbial reality
也让我们散落到了不同的时间里
also scattered us across time.
我还以为我的精神出问题了
Man, I thought I was going crazy.
你来这里多久了
How long have you been here?
来了1128天6个小时零...20分钟了
One thousand, one hundred twenty-eight days, six hours, and twenty minutes.
大差不差的
Give or take.
所以你待了这么久 就是为了等我
So you've just been waiting for me all this time?
可以这么说 或者...
Precisely. Or
也可以不这么说
rather, imprecisely.
即便我寿命比一般人长
I grew skeptical you'd arrive,
但我也不敢确定能不能真的等到你
even during my unusually long lifetime.
那杰斯呢 他也来了吗
What about Jayce? Is he here?
我猜他恐怕是去了别的时空了
I fear he may have wound up elsewhere.
异常点在他身上产生的效果不一样
The anomaly behaved differently around him.
你应该有办法能把我们带回去的吧
Tell me you figured out a way to get us home.
你这话倒是把我难倒了
That is a veritable conundrum.
要是这里发明不出海克斯科技的话
I'm afraid Hextech was never invented here.
那么也自然就造不出 海克斯飞门这种神奇的东西了
And without a creation so prodigious as the Hexgates...
也没有异常点了
No anomaly.
哎呀 也没那么糟糕
Oh, it isn't all bad.
我在这个世界就干了不少很棒的事
I've been able to accomplish wonderful things in this world.
给自己点时间
Give it time to settle.
你也一定会越来越适应这里的
This place will grow on you. You'll see.
适应这里
Grow on me?
原来的那个世界还有人需要我
I have people back home who need me.
我们不属于这里
We don't belong here.
可我们暂时还回不去
And yet we can't leave.
算了 我自己想办法回去 你爱帮不帮
I'm gonna find a way back, with or without you.
我准备一会儿去看看蔚
I was gonna go see Vi.
蔚
Vi?
要不一起去
You wanna come?
我们究竟做了什么
What have we done?
有人吗
Hello?
有没有人啊
Is anyone out there?
谁
是什么人
Who's there?
是你
You.
是你带我来的吗
Did you bring me here?
这是什么地方
Where are we?
等等
Wait!
不
No.
怎么可能
It can't be.
哪来这么多问题 艾克
What's with the third degree, Ekko?
弄得跟这不是你的项目似的
We've been working on this for months.
你就说吧
Humor me.
当初是你信誓旦旦地说
You had one of your funky dreams
你那个能量储存装置的离谱设想
about an energy-storage device
一定能赢得竞赛 所以...
that you swore would win the competition. So
你才来找我帮忙的
you came to me for help.
我找你帮忙
I came to you?
因为你怕你自己搞不定啊
You weren't gonna figure it out yourself.
项目“零” 零损耗化学能量单元
"Zero-loss chemical energy cell."
那这个设想...
And this invention.
你没有想过把它用到其他地方吗
You don't have some alternative purpose for it?
这事儿问你自己才对吧
You're the big idea guy.
抱歉 姐姐
Sorry, sis.
有个人正在为他的项目头疼
Someone's wigging out over his project
而且又在打退堂鼓
and having an identity crisis again.
名字不提了
No names.
范德尔说我没有 把自己的潜力用对地方
I got the "not living up to my potential" speech from Vander again.
他一说这话 我就总想到你
Reminds me of you.
她死了
She's dead?
怎么死的
How?
别开这种玩笑 艾克
That's not funny, Ekko.
我真的不该来这儿的
It was a mistake to come here.
你说这话什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
你自己心里有不痛快
Just 'cause you're having a bad day,
也别拿我撒气
don't take it out on me.
是因为你吗
Was it you?
是你给我们递的信
You gave us the tip.
我们去干了那一票 都是因为你
We went on that job because of you.
那一票 怪不得这里没有海克斯科技
The job. That's why there's no Hextech here.
你还是走吧 快走
You should leave.
别让我干出后悔的事
Go. Before I do something I regret.
说实话 我也没想留下
Believe me, I'm working on it.
等等我
快来 快来这边
Come on. I saw it over here.
你要喝茶吗 先生
Care for a cup of tea, sir?
得了
Come on.
(理发店)
看轮盘转动 将停留何方
沉浸喧嚣 舞一曲何妨
战火已悄然熄灭 音乐奏响
朋友们啊 走吧
让一切随风
与至亲分享你的人生见闻
若你能 爱上这旅程 莫问终点
出发
我将那沙漏翻转 默数十声
不需要道别
蔚奥莱 不要 求你不要死
Violet, don't! Ple--
不要
Please, no...
才刚启程
朋友走吧
求你了
别太在意遗憾 这才是人生
若尘埃落定 就无问西东
就让清风拂过 燃起篝火
齿轮转动 朋友
让它转动
谢谢大家
Thank you very much.
你觉得靠这些就能让异常点重现了
You think you can recreate the anomaly with these?
理论上行
That's the theory.
想法倒是不错
Inconceivable.
你愿意帮我吗
So you'll help me?
我只是说想法不错
I meant that quite literally.
可没说真的可以去这么干
I don't believe this can be done.
贸然使用奥术 是不会有好下场的 小伙子
Tampering with the Arcane never ends well, lad.
风险实在太大了
The risk is far too great.
你说过我是你的学生
You said I was your pupil.
我需要你的指导
I need a professor.
要能成为搭档 就更好了
Better yet, a partner.
我的机械祖师爷
Oh, blast nozzles.
我果然是不忍心拒绝青年才俊啊
How could I forsake a brilliant lad in need?
老毛病了
Again.
我就该承受这些吗
I never asked for this.
这个研究是我的一切 是我的毕生心血
That research is everything. My whole life.
他曾是我的导师 我却背弃了他
He was my mentor, Mel. And I betrayed him.
你们必须摧毁它
You must destroy it.
它腐蚀了人心 耗尽了资源
It corrupts. Consumes.
我本来是想创造魔法的
I was trying to create magic.
- 皮尔特沃夫的未来 - 是你的时代了 杰斯
- Piltover... - It's your time now, Jayce.
也许是时候
Perhaps it's time.
不 不
No, no.
开启魔法的纪元了
For the era of magic.
无数城邦的毁灭 都来自一颗邪恶的种子
I've seen nations destroyed...
- 别这样 - 而这个就跟那些一样
- Please. - ...exactly like this.
小心脚下
Watch your step.
我们快到了
We're almost there.
艾克 我不知道你想干什么
I don't know what this is all about,
如果你是要道歉的话
but if you're trying to apologize,
把我拽到一个...
dragging me through the...
这都是
你自己画的
You painted this?
我做了一个梦
I had this dream...
梦里的一切都是相反的
where things went another way.
她看起来挺不好惹的
She looks so badass.
何止是不好惹
You don't know the half of it.
这家伙在底城可是打遍天下无敌手
She was the toughest person in all of Zaun.
无所畏惧
Nothing scared her.
我姐才不是这样
No, not my sister.
她外表坚强 内心却很脆弱
Vi was strong because she was afraid.
她一直拼尽全力
Her fear of losing us is
只是因为害怕失去我们
what made her fight so hard.
在我梦里 你也变了个样
You were different in my dream too.
是吗 小子
Oh, yeah, buster?
在这儿等着我呢 是吧
Is that what this is about?
想求我改变
You want me to change?
没有
No.
没有 只是
No, no, I just...
你不应该是那个
You aren't the kind of person
那个去帮助别人实现梦想的人
who helps other people with their projects.
你的想法能改变这个世界
Your ideas change the world.
我一直都这么认为
I can't shake the feeling that
那才是你该有的样子
that's who you're supposed to be.
现在挺好的 艾克
Things are good, Ekko.
我...我现在很开心
I like my life.
我不想为了追逐所谓的梦想去改变
I don't wanna lose what makes me "me"
去变成另一副模样
chasing some wild dream.
有时候 向前一步
Sometimes taking a leap
往往意味着需要舍弃一些东西
forward means leaving a few things behind.
你有时候真是让人猜不透啊
You're a real mystery, aren't you, mister?
好了 别绕弯子了
All right, out with it.
到底想让我干嘛
What do you want from me?
这也太小了
It's so small.
天哪
Golly,
竟然做到了
we've done it.
这才哪到哪啊
Halfway there.
所以这玩意儿有什么用
So, what does it do?
你刚刚不是问过我了吗
You just asked me that.
我没问过
No, I didn't.
我现在没心情陪你玩游戏
I'm too tired for games.
我没问过
No, I didn't.
这是时间循环
It's a time loop.
时间循环
Huh? A time loop?
- Huh? A time loop? - A time loop.
你刚才回到过去了吗
You're going back in time.
机械祖师爷啊 歪打正着还真就成了
Gadzooks. How did you stumble upon that?
我试了一下把杰斯的 加速符文反转过来操作
I was playing with inversions on Jayce's acceleration rune.
那你回去了多久
How far did you go?
不知道 一秒钟
I don't know. A second?
试试能不能再久一点
Try going back further.
嘿嘿 先别着急 小伙子
Take it slow, lad.
搞发明创造得一步步来
We wouldn't want to push a new invention too
不能操之过急
far too quickly.
一
One.
二
Two.
三
Three.
祖师爷
Gadzooks.
四
Four.
最多只能倒回去四秒
The limit is four seconds.
真的吗 小伙子
Are you certain, my boy?
你怎么这么肯定啊
What were the indicators?
相信我
Trust me.
真的只有四秒
It's four seconds.
很厉害了
Amazing.
我们去派对 让大伙见识一下
We could show it off at the party.
目前还不行
We aren't done.
别忘了换身衣服再去派对
Please go change before the party.
我来试试看能不能给它增增效
I think I might know how to give it a boost.
增效
A boost?
你就当给它升个级 临时的
A momentary upgrade, if you will.
太好了 我们怎么开始
That's great. Where do we start?
就从你去参加派对开始吧
You can start by attending your party.
人在独处时更容易集中精神
One's thoughts are more easily gathered in isolation.
如果不能好好享受当下
And what's the point of a device like this
那造这个装置出来还有什么意义呢
if you don't enjoy the time you have?
原来你在这儿啊
There he is.
嘿 紧张吗 小子
Hey, nervous, kid?
明天可是大日子呀
Big day tomorrow.
我这也正犯愁呢
It's all I can think about.
那小姑娘在哪呢
Where's the little lady?
不知道
Not sure.
她好像说了要来个什么惊艳登场
She said something about making an entrance.
她还真是喜欢搞花样 对吧
She does love a spectacle, eh?
是啊
Yeah.
我怕我明天来不及跟你说 所以...
Hey, in case I don't remember to tell you tomorrow,
你一直是我最重要的人 本索
you've always meant the world to me, Benzo.
我...你那个...
Well, you, uh...
你怎么还多愁善感上了
Uh, you... Oh, don't get all mushy on me now.
怎么把一个大男人给弄哭了
Making the big man misty, are you?
该死的过敏怎么又犯了
Oh, these damned allergies.
你应该为自己感到骄傲 艾克
You should be proud of yourself, Ekko.
那个Z型驱动器 爆爆觉得特了不起
Powder's been raving about your Z-Drive.
我都好久没见她对什么事这么激动了
Can't remember the last time I saw her so alive.
我有预感 这地方迟早得听你的
I have the feeling that you'll be running this place soon.
看来我们得抓紧机会了
So there's a chance for us yet.
你
You?
你的大日子 我怎么能错过呢 是不是
Didn't think I'd miss your big day, did you?
你不是想要杀了他吗
Didn't you try to kill him?
人生中最重要的一课
Greatest thing we can do in life is find
就是要学会释怀
the power to forgive.
(创新者竞赛)
今晚很特别
Some night.
这里真美啊
It's beautiful.
那些舞步你从哪儿学的
Where'd you learn those moves?
我只是在跟着你跳
Oh, I was just following your lead.
还挺会说的
He's got lines.
那个
Hey. Uh...
我想说 谢谢你
I just want to thank you.
谢谢你做的一切
You know, for everything.
我幻想中的底城也像现在这么美好
I used to dream the undercity could be like this.
可不知从什么时候起 我...
But somewhere, I
眼里就只能看见它的不堪
got consumed by all the ways it wasn't.
我放弃过它
I gave up on it.
也放弃过你
Gave up on you.
我从来没见你真的放弃过什么 艾克
I've never seen you give up on anything, Ekko.
有没有那么一刻
You ever wish you could
时间能就此停住
just stay in one moment?
有时候
Sometimes
想要向前一步 意味着
taking a leap forward means...
必须舍弃一些东西
leaving a few things behind.
这一刻 我永远都不会忘记
I promise I'll never forget this.
最好是这样
You better not.
对不起 我...
Sorry, I...
不 没关系
No... It's fine,
我...
I...
能不能倒回去
Can we just pretend
假装刚刚什么都没发生
like it's the first time?
艾克 小伙子 你回来得正好
Ekko, my lad. You're just in time.
你这增效增得也太大了吧
This is a big upgrade.
稍等一下
Just a moment.
我把最后几处电源接上 就大功告成了
I only need to hook up the final power supply.
这就是一切开始的地方
This is where it all started, isn't it?
海克斯科技
The end of Piltover.
毁了皮尔特沃夫
Because of Hextech.
为什么你要给我这个
Why did you ever give me this?
为什么
Why?
本来不会变成这样的 对不对
It doesn't have to go this way, right?
告诉我还有挽回的余地
Just tell me there's a chance.
早知道是这样 就该和爆爆道个歉
Oh, I do wish I could apologize to Ms. Powder
这玩意儿太占地方了
for co-opting her space like this.
希望她不会太介意
It truly was the only way.
把我送回去
Send me back.
每一刻都精彩绝伦
Never a dull moment.
不得不说 认识了你这个小伙子
I must say that since I've met you, lad,
- 我也此生无憾了 - 什么
- I've truly lived. - What?
- 我去去就来 - 不要
- Back in a wink. - No!
黑默丁格 等等
Heimerdinger, wait! Wait!
我不会失败的
I won't fail.
绝对不会
I swear it.
不
No!
爆爆
Powder?
这是怎么了
What happened?
(蔚)
字幕翻译: 付博文 韩一旻